Pardon me.
Excuse me. Step aside please.
Jesus Christ.
Lee's Diner. I got four down.
I need two EMS vehicles.
What the hell happened here?
Somebody run them over?
No, man, it was a fight.
One guy took them all out
in like seconds.
He's still in there.
That's him.
Turn around, mister.
Let me see your hands.
Slowly.
Military ID.
Expired.
Thirty-eight bucks.
And a toothbrush.
But no home address.
In other words, homeless.
Aggravated assault
is a second-degree felony
in this state, Mister...
Reacher. First name Jack.
No middle name.
You're looking at 10 to 20 years
once those boys you beat
out there are fit to testify.
Process him. Get him to County.
Two things are gonna happen
in the next 90 seconds.
Excuse me?
First, that phone over there
is gonna ring.
And second...
You're gonna be wearing these cuffs
on your way to prison.
Well, that is one magnificent
prophecy, Mr. Reacher.
That'll be a Major Turner
of the 110th C.I.D. Military Police
in Alexandria, Virginia.
You and those boys out there
made a mistake
operating on land
owned by the U.S. Army.
What are you talking about?
Kidnapping illegals.
Selling them.
MPs are on their way now.
If it were up to me, I'd just kill you.
It's just gonna keep on ringing.
Sheriff Raymond Wood.
Who the hell are you?
The guy you didn't count on.
Thank you.
United States Army, 110.
Sergeant Leach.
Major Turner, please.
One moment, please.
This is Turner.
Major S. Turner?
This is she.
Who am I speaking to?
Jack Reacher.
No kidding.
Well, it's nice to finally speak.
Thanks for tipping us off to that Sheriff.
No, I...
I wanted to thank you
for helping me out of a tight spot.
Isn't that what Army folks
do for each other, Major?
Ex-Major.
Oh, once a Major, always a Major.
Where are you calling from?
Outside Independence, I think.
You're not sure.
It doesn't really matter.
I move around a lot.
- So I've heard.
- What else have you heard?
Oh, come on.
You're a legend around here.
Some folks still wonder why you left.
Let's just say I woke up one morning
and the uniform didn't fit.
United States Army, 110.
Sergeant Leach.
Jack Reacher for Major Turner.
Hold on, Major.
Reacher.
How's my office?
I'm sitting here now.
Uh, there is this big dent in the desk.
And people say you made it
with someone's head.
Is that true?
Not my finest hour.
You're not
in trouble again, are you?
I've heard you have a way of finding it.
Or looking for it.
Yeah, I was thinking
maybe I owe you dinner
for what you did.
Oh, well, it took you a while
to come to that conclusion.
When are you coming to D.C.?
I'll get there eventually.
Well, then I won't
hold my breath.
You're not saying anything.
I'm deciding whether
I'd like you in person.
Which way you leaning?
On the fence.
Not sure you could handle me.
I am not worried.
Oh, worry. Just a little.
Take care of yourself, Reacher.
Jack Reacher for Major Turner.
Major Reacher. Sergeant Leach.
We've spoken on the phone.
Welcome back.
Just Reacher.
I'm a civilian now.
Yes, sir. I'll take you up.
I'm sorry. I was...
- Looking for the Major?
- Come in.
Sam Morgan. Please, come in.
Come in.
Have a seat.
Heard a lot about you.
Just stopping by to see Major Turner.
Oh... Well, that's a problem.
Major Turner's been relieved
of her command.
I spoke with her a few days ago.
She's been arrested.
Court-martial's pending.
On what charge?
Espionage.
I'm assuming her duties until
a replacement is assigned.
Something I can help you with?
No. Just a personal visit.
You know each other from
back when you were C.O. here?
Nope. Never met.
I'm sorry to give you
the bad news, Major.
Ex-Major.
Sir, I wanted to warn you.
- But?
- Ordered not to.
Colonel Morgan directly.
Maybe you should warn me now.
Speak freely, Sergeant.
Major Turner is an excellent officer, sir.
Has she been assigned an attorney yet?
Ordered not to give out any
information about that, sir.
Understood.
Always follow orders, Sergeant.
Sir.
Just curious.
Who was your D.I. in boot camp?
Sergeant Greene, sir.
Now, say if Sergeant Greene
were having legal troubles,
would you be able to recommend
an attorney for him?
Oh. Yes. Definitely.
I'd recommend Colonel Moorcroft
over at Fort Dyer
where the high-security
prisoners are confined, sir.
Colonel?
You're the assigned counsel
for Major Susan Turner.
I'm Jack Reacher,
former commander of the 110th.
I was wondering
when you were gonna show up.
Major Turner requested
under no circumstances
are you to be
granted visitation privileges.
- Why would she say that?
- Maybe she read your file.
"Anti-authority, anti-social..."
- Anti-lawyer.
- Deadbeat dad?
Excuse me?
It says here
you never paid child support.
I'm not a father.
Well, a woman named
Candace Dutton begs to differ.
She contacted the Army
seeking compensation
for her daughter, Samantha Dutton.
She's 15 now.
- It's a mistake.
- They usually are.
Mother's got two priors...
Prostitution. Possession.
The kid's been in and out
of foster care her whole life.
- Any feelings about that?
- About foster care?
Life sucks.
I meant the kid.
I don't have a kid.
I've never heard of Candace Dutton.
I'm here about Major Turner.
What evidence do they have?
A hard drive containing
classified information
found in Major Turner's residence.
The inference being
she's selling secrets.
And that's it?
What do you want, a picture
of her wearing a burka
having drinks with the Taliban?
What did she tell you?
Can't talk to her until tomorrow.
Public Safety Exception.
And you accepted that?
Where'd you get your law degree?
Oh...
It's possible you were once
a good lawyer, Colonel.
But what I see
is a tired lifer who'll do anything
not to endanger his pension.
Let me know when you remember
what that uniform stands for.
Thank you.
How long are we supposed to do this?
I'm getting hungry.
Just be patient.
What do you think
he's eating?
Shut up.
- New gun?
- Yep.
Oh, it's nice.
It makes your hands look big.
Yeah, you like big hands?
Put one of these in your face
in a minute, you carry on.
Hey. Hey, hey! Where'd he go?
I don't know. Maybe went to the pisser.
You're supposed to be watching him.
What do you think I got,
eyes in the back of me head?
How's it going?
Don't.
Show me.
Throw it in back.
I don't like being followed.
On the sidewalk before.
And in the market.
You're a little thief.
- You a cop?
- I look like a cop?
Narc maybe.
You know a lot of narcs?
It's the haircut.
Well, thanks. I did it myself.
So, you're looking for something weird.
See ya.
Are you Candace Dutton's daughter?
- What'd she do this time?
- Nothing.
I'm an old friend.
Yeah?
Well, she's not into doing
that kind of thing anymore.
That's not what I meant.
If you're looking for my mom,
I don't live with her.
Who do you live with?
You were right, Major.
I am tired.
But I'm not stupid.
Sergeants Mirkovich and Cibelli.
Two weeks ago,
Major Turner dispatches them
to Afghanistan on an investigation.
They file reports daily.
Two days ago, they're both found dead
near Bagram Air Base.
Shot at close range.
And the next day,
Major Turner's thrown in prison.
What do you know about Parasource?
Parasource?
It's a big military contractor. Why?
I don't know how
they're involved in all this,
but they've been following me
since I got here.
Whoever killed Mirkovich and Cibelli
wanted Major Turner isolated.
I think they're gonna kill her, too.
What are you talking about?
We have no idea if any
of these things are connected.
We need to get her out.
And might I reiterate,
she does not want you involved.
Do it now. And I'll call you tonight.
People question the value
of enhanced interrogation techniques.
Enhanced interrogation
techniques don't work.
But torture, on the other hand,
works very well.
Attorney-client privilege
goes back to the earliest days
of English Common Law.
It means that Major Turner
told you in confidence
a great deal about what she learned
from her investigation in Afghanistan.
How much did you tell Jack Reacher?
We didn't talk about that.
Of course you did.
Mmm-mmm...
We talked for 10 minutes.
Ten minutes is a very long time,
as you are about to learn.
Jack Reacher?
Colonel Morgan was wondering
if you had a few minutes.
You don't remember me, do you?
Anthony Espin?
Nah. You were still C.O.
when I got here.
Held back my promotion for six months.
Why'd I do that?
'Cause you were
a hard-ass prick who said
I jumped to conclusions.
I'm sure I jumped to conclusions.
Have a seat.
You're under no obligation
to say anything, Major.
Ex-Major.
Upon leaving yesterday,
did you attempt to contact
Major Turner?
Did you confront her attorney,
Colonel Moorcroft,
at Fort Dyer at 1100?
You told me not to say anything.
I said you didn't have to say anything.
Yes.
Yes, you confronted him?
Yes, I understand
I don't have to say anything.
For the record, you did confront
Colonel Moorcroft yesterday.
Can you state your
whereabouts last night
between 0130 and 0500?
Yes.
Yes, what?
Yes, I understand
I don't have to say anything.
Note for the record, the Major
has an injury to his hand
not present during yesterday's meeting.
We're done here.
At approximately 0230 this morning,
Colonel Archibald Moorcroft
was beaten to death.
You're my attorney.
Lieutenant Sullivan. How do you do?
You are hereby charged
with the murder
of a Judge Advocate General...
- Where was he killed?
- In his apartment.
- Off base.
- Yes.
This is a civilian matter.
As a private citizen,
the Army has no jurisdiction.
Turn me over to the D.C. police.
You're familiar with Article
10.75 of the Military Code?
An officer with your security clearance
remains subject to recall
in event of emergency.
You agreed to it
when you signed your discharge.
Welcome back to the Army, Major.
You're under arrest.
Open BA211.
Stand here. Don't move.
Espin, prisoner transfer.
I'll file for disclosure.
They'll turn over whatever
evidence they have on you.
There won't be any evidence.
What are you talking about?
They killed her investigators,
they killed her lawyer.
Evidence suggests
you killed Major Turner's lawyer.
They're gonna kill her,
then they're gonna kill me.
For all I know, you're part of it.
Hey, listen, dickhead.
You're the one accused of murder.
You wanna show me
a shred of evidence,
I'll defend you till kingdom come.
Otherwise, go to hell.
I apologize.
I think I have low blood sugar.
- Excuse me?
- I didn't eat this morning,
feel lightheaded.
Could you get me something
from the officers' mess?
Sandwich, maybe.
Open the door, please.
We're done here.
Move.
Open BA201.
Ma'am, these men are here
to transfer you.
Who are they?
I asked you a question.
Are you gonna answer me?
Reacher?
Halt!
Stand down!
These men are here to kill you.
- They killed Moorcroft.
- Wait, what?
Last night, in his apartment.
And now they're gonna kill you.
Soldier! You know who I am!
I need you to stand down!
You've been relieved
of command, ma'am.
Turner, no time.
I'm being held here without cause.
It is your right to counter...
That soldier was under my command!
We don't have time for this.
Get his badge and his papers.
I left explicit orders
for you to stay away.
- Orders? You "ordered" me?
- Yes.
I knew you'd do something like this.
Don't make me regret it.
Espin? What'd you do to him?
He'll be fine.
- This is insane.
- Does this mean dinner's off?
- Act angry.
- I am angry.
Prisoner transfer.
Lieutenant Sullivan coming in.
Open BA211.
- Hey, wait a second!
- Move!
His keys! Give me his keys!
What kind of car
would my lawyer be driving?
A black sedan.
Survey the perimeter!
Secure the service lot!
- Move! Move! Close in!
- Let's go!
Food truck.
Clear!
They're in the food truck!
Stop that truck! Go, go, go, go!
Go, go!
Get them out of that truck!
Clear!
So now I'm a fugitive from justice.
And a traitor to your country,
don't forget that.
Why do I feel like you're enjoying this?
You have a very interesting way
of saying thank you.
Were those men really going to kill me?
Thank you.
Nice job.
Oh, his ass is mine.
X.O. One of our vehicles
has been hijacked. L67.
All units. Suspects traveling.
MP vehicle L67.
Primary is Jack Reacher.
White. Male. 40s.
Considered armed and dangerous.
Secondary is Major Susan Turner.
Female. Wearing military fatigues.
White. Age 34.
- Really?
- Shut up.
We need to ditch this car
and get into my email.
All right, people, let's go, let's go!
Where the hell are they?
Specialist, have the State Troopers
called back yet?
On it, sir.
All right, has anybody heard
from the Capitol Police?
Anybody? Anything?
A location? Something?
Is there still an Internet café
around here?
Pennsylvania and North Street.
Okay. Take us there, please.
I should have gone
to Afghanistan myself.
Mirkovich and Cibelli
were my responsibility.
The job is about giving orders.
You ever lose anyone
on your watch, Reacher?
My men weren't killed by the Taliban.
They were shot, in the back of the head,
with slugs from an Army-issued 9mm.
By one of our own.
I'm gonna find out who did it.
What were your guys doing over there?
What were they looking for?
Weapons.
Thousands of weapons,
decommissioned during the drawdown.
Whole plane load's gone missing.
Hey, I like your hat.
- You a Nats fan?
- Yeah, from the beginning.
They arrested me the day after
my investigators were killed.
With the time difference,
they might have filed another report.
They locked me up so I wouldn't see it.
Sir, she's trying to access the system.
- Get me that location.
- Yes, sir.
Pennsylvania and North Street.
It's Morgan.
Ready to go to work, soldier?
We've located them.
They're at an Internet café,
Pennsylvania and North Street.
Get it done.
Whatever Mi rkovich
and Cibelli found out
got them killed.
But by who?
Shit. They locked me out.
They're gonna triangulate
this I.P. address.
I know. Just give me a second. Okay?
- They will know this location.
- Let me try one last thing.
- Shit.
There's a bus stop
on the other side of the park.
We're being followed.
It's not a cop.
He's a pro.
Where?
Fifty yards.
Black coat, brown hair.
There.
- They made us.
- Maybe.
Restaurant.
Hello.
We're meeting someone in the back.
- Everybody out!
- Let's go!
- Out!
- Move!
Come on! Go, go!
I got this door.
Stay back! Stay back!
No, don't. Stay back!
Police! Freeze!
Drop your weapon.
Sir, I said drop your weapon.
I'm military police!
He's not a cop!
Sir, drop your weapon!
I'm military police.
Sir, I need you to drop your weapon.
Listen, I know what this looks like.
Sir, turn around
and let me see your hands!
I'm putting my weapon down.
Listen to me.
I'm military police.
These two are fugitives
of the United States Army.
I understand. I'm turning around.
Place your hands
behind your head. Now!
My identification's
in my right front pocket.
Will you just check it?
Just check.
Go! Move, move! Go!
We got our signals crossed.
He's good.
We'll get him next time.
You know, I admit to being
a little jealous when we talk.
Go where you want.
Eat when you want.
Nobody telling you
what to do or how to do it.
It's definitely not the Army way.
Exactly.
Let's take a look at that registration.
Parasource?
You think that guy in the kitchen
was one of theirs?
Freelance is my guess.
Go.
Made a mess, I hear.
This Reacher guy is interesting.
You have no idea.
They ran out of medals.
So don't make this a competition.
Too late.
Sure you can handle him by yourself?
I can handle him just fine.
Prove it.
- Coffee?
- Cream?
No.
Right sizes.
Good eye.
I spent the rest of our cash.
It's time we stopped running
and start hunting.
Morgan.
Catch you at a bad time?
I hope you're calling
to turn yourselves in.
I don't know your role
in this yet, Colonel.
I'm guessing money.
I promise you I will find out.
Nobody's gonna find anything.
Not even in Major Turner's email?
- Find it yet?
- Nothing to find.
You're not looking hard enough.
Why don't we check my field reports?
I will snap the tendon
before it breaks the bone.
It takes longer to heal.
Locked. Need the code.
1209#.
Mirkovich and Cibelli's field reports.
What else you got on here, huh?
You think you're invulnerable.
Almost done uploading.
But there are ways to get
at you, Reacher.
Got it.
Thanks for all your help, Colonel.
Okay. Mirkovich and Cibelli
did file a final report.
"Warlords..."
Okay, here we go.
The last man they spoke to
was a contractor
named Daniel Prudhomme.
He oversaw weapons transports.
Said he was evasive
then he disappeared.
This is Leach.
This is Sergeant Greene,
your old D.I. Remember me?
Sergeant Greene.
So good to hear from you.
I'm here
with a friend of yours.
We need a favor.
There's a military contractor
called Parasource.
Think you could ask around,
find out what role
they played in Bagram?
I might be able to do that.
Also there's a Parasource
employee named Prudhomme.
We need his whereabouts.
Prudhomme. Copy that.
And, Sergeant.
Carefully.
Sir, yes, sir.
Reacher.
Clear.
Hey, stop, hey!
Let go of me!
- Let go of me! Let go!
- Hey, hey, hey!
Samantha.
It's okay. It's okay.
I don't understand.
You said you're not a cop.
I'm not.
What's military police?
It's different.
But you stole this car.
It's complicated.
Where are you taking me?
We don't know yet.
- Hey, do you have a phone?
- Why?
Just give it to me.
I left it in the apartment
where you kidnapped me.
We didn't kidnap you.
Kidnapping is a federal offense.
Look at me, kid.
There are people out there
who want to hurt you.
I feel sick.
Just put your head out the window.
It doesn't open.
Hey, when was the last time
you had something to eat?
- I don't know.
- We need to get her some food.
How long have you been drawing?
I don't know. Why?
Just asking.
They suck.
Whatever you say.
Beth and Herb were these
two nice old hippies.
Who'd want to kill them?
You've had a shock.
Your body's pumping adrenaline.
Cortisol. They call it fight or flight.
It's gonna take a while to calm down.
Here.
I can't eat. I'm pumping adrenaline.
I know a place she'll be safe.
What does that mean?
I'm not going to a stupid school.
They have a dress code.
This is what they wear there.
I know the headmistress.
You'll be safe there.
"Headmistress?" What is it, a convent?
Do you want to live?
Do you?
Yes.
Then you will go where we say
and stay until we say it's safe.
Do you understand?
You're very intense. You know that?
Yeah, I understand.
- What are you doing here?
- Reacher has the girl.
You were supposed to take care of that.
You people.
You take off the uniform
and lose all discipline.
How did he find her?
Exactly.
How did he?
How would I know?
When he was here, earlier today.
You're watching me now?
Who the hell do you think you are?
What did you give him?
What are you talking about?
I don't have to be interrogated
by the likes of you.
He came in here with that
bitch and threatened me.
I gave him nothing.
What's so funny?
We hired you to clean up this mess.
You're right.
He touched this phone, didn't he?
So?
That means his prints are on it. Huh?
I mean, really,
if I had any other choice...
It should only be for a few days.
You know how we feel about
you here at Pembroke, Susan.
Well, thank you.
- It's so nice to see you.
- It's good to see you, too...
Show me what you feel.
You are not a camera.
What do you feel about these hands?
Are these nurturing hands?
Have they held children?
Do they carry pain?
Why do we draw?
Welcome to Pembroke. Hi, I'm Olivia.
And I'm May.
Carla.
Come sit with us.
Where'd you go before this?
Different places.
Ooh, travel's really good
for college applications.
Have you taken the PSATs yet?
You need to sign up right away.
May! Oh, my God, your earrings!
Where'd you get them?
Oh, thank you. Actually, my dad
brought them back from New York.
Ah! My parents promised me
some intense retail therapy
when we're in Paris for Christmas.
Wow, Paris.
You guys have been everywhere.
It's beautiful. I've been three times.
Have you ever been?
- No, actually not.
- Can you imagine Christmas?
- It's great. The Eiffel Tower.
- Have you been in it?
Yeah, three times, girl!
Aren't you going to Spain?
You guys are doing
a lot of traveling.
It's awesome.
I'll probably stick around at home.
The usual.
She's gonna do fine.
I don't want you to worry.
What are you doing?
You said you didn't have a phone.
How many times did you use this?
In my life?
Let's go. Get your things.
It was nothing. Just one person.
- Excuse me. We have to go. Thank you.
- It was nothing.
Nance, give me one second. Hey!
Hey, what the hell is going on?
- She was texting.
- Shit!
- What's wrong with that?
- One, they can trace us.
Come on, let's go.
Get in.
God, that place was ridiculous.
That place changed my life.
Sorry about the phone.
Go.
Did some digging about Parasource.
Some of their boys
got into trouble in Afghanistan.
They lost some
big government contracts.
Word is they're in financial trouble.
Why does he get to have a phone?
- This Daniel Prudhomme...
- Hold on. You need to be quiet.
'Kay, sorry. Daniel Prudhomme.
Keep going.
The contractor our guys talked to,
he lives in New Orleans.
He disappeared right after
he was interrogated.
Hitched a ride back home
to his wife and kids.
New Orleans
is Parasource's home base.
They know he's back
and they're looking for him.
We're going to New Orleans.
- Sir, there's something else.
- Yep?
Colonel Morgan was killed.
Your prints were found
on the murder weapon.
Appreciate your help, Sergeant.
We need to find Prudhomme
before Parasource gets a hold of him.
There's an airport at Norfolk.
- We'll need credit cards.
- And IDs.
American Express. Visa.
Discover.
"Daddy is so happy with my SATs
and extracurricular activities,
"he's takin' us all to New Orleans."
Unless you want me to shut up.
You little shit.
Sure about this?
No.
Want me to do it?
Tan jacket.
Yeah.
- I'm sorry.
- Excuse me.
No problem.
Enjoy your flight.
If you're seated
in an emergency exit row,
please review the responsibilities
for emergency exit seating
on the back
of the safety information card
located in the seat pocket
in front of you.
Haven't flown before?
Here.
You're kidding.
I don't want you puking on me.
I'm not gonna puke.
Good.
So, how long have you been
in the Army for?
Uh...
- Ten years.
- Oh, wow.
- What's your rank?
- Major.
So, if you give a guy orders,
he has to obey.
Like, fast.
Yeah.
And if he tries messing with you,
you know, like, all kinds of moves, right?
A few.
Oh, that's badass.
Can I learn some?
Sure.
- You're not married, right?
- No.
Are you gay?
I mean, it's totally cool.
I know tons of lesbians.
No, I'm not gay.
I thought all lady soldiers are gay.
Well, some are, some aren't.
Like out in the real world.
So, is Reacher
your boyfriend?
No.
- Friends with benefits.
- Uh, no.
You mean no, you don't want to,
or no, he doesn't want to, or no, not yet,
you guys haven't really...
All right. I see how it is.
My dad was military.
Really?
Never met him.
He left before I was born.
Where was he stationed?
Around D.C., I guess.
What was his name?
Candy won't talk about him.
- Candy? Oh.
- My mom.
Just says he was a big hero
and a total asshole.
We're beginning our descent,
so if you need to stretch your
legs or use the lavatories,
you should do it now.
I'll be right back.
It's the haircut.
All you contractors
go to the same barber?
Check it.
Oh, he's not feeling well.
You might want to use this one.
Go.
Took two more of your pieces
off the board.
They were the B team.
What were you? JSOC? SEAL Team?
- Something like that.
- When'd you get back?
I'm not sure I ever did.
Don't you miss it?
Not a bit.
I think you do, drifter.
People like us,
we can never go back to the world.
We hurt people.
And the people around us get hurt.
Leave Turner to me.
Walk away now and I won't
hurt the little girl.
You coming to New Orleans?
I'm thinking about it.
Look me up.
I will.
Stairs. Go, go, go.
Go! Go!
Go.
Go. Go.
Wait, wait, wait!
Welcome to Louis Armstrong
New Orleans International Airport.
Now, you're gonna tell me
what's going on,
or the first chance I get,
I'm gonna scream
or grab a policeman.
- Okay, look...
- We're protecting you.
- I found out that some...
- Look, you don't...
- Can you stop?
- Just...
Some people were stealing
from the government.
Stealing what?
At this point,
the less you know, the better.
Bullshit! I got us the credit card, okay?
We wouldn't have gotten
on that plane without it.
They're after me, too.
Why?
You need to tell her.
They think you're my daughter.
That's funny?
You're not my father.
How do you know?
Well, why would you think you are?
Because your mother
filed a paternity suit
with the Army claiming I was.
All we have available
is a lovely two-bedroom suite,
$350 a night. Will that do?
Yes. Can I pay in cash?
So, we gonna take a DNA test?
Little busy right now.
I got to tell you something.
You're gonna get angry.
This whole thing is my fault.
How's that?
I was the one who made her
file the paternity thing.
I thought maybe
she could get something out of it.
Money.
Child support.
Help her get her life together.
She's doing better since she got out.
Got a job.
Maybe she could get a little house.
You're mad.
I can see it in your face.
I'm not mad.
Yes, you are. They think I'm your kid,
so you have to worry about
protecting me.
Yeah.
So?
So I don't want to be here.
So you don't want me here.
So I should just leave.
Okay.
Where you gonna go?
I got, uh, food.
- Oh, God!
- Thanks.
- I'm starving. Thanks.
- Yeah.
She's out.
Our dinner date.
Champagne is still chilling.
I knew you were the romantic type.
So, Reacher, after those phone calls,
what exactly
did you think would happen?
I thought a nice dinner,
maybe some wine.
And after dinner?
Back to your place, maybe.
As opposed to your seedy motel?
Never underestimate the charm
of a seedy motel.
I can see the appeal.
What do you say
we look for a seedy motel
once I find Prudhomme?
I'll go with you.
Only one of us should go.
So I'll go.
No, someone needs to stay here
with her.
What, because I'm a woman
I should be the babysitter?
I don't know how to be the babysitter.
- You think that I do?
- Yes.
You know, I've had to
put up with this crap
my entire career.
Forget the dickheads
who think that they can paw me,
- it's every male officer...
- Hey, hey, excuse me.
...who thinks that he's smarter
and tougher...
You've been relieved of command.
I am the commanding officer here!
You are a fugitive from military justice.
So are you!
So we're both criminals.
I'm going.
That's a bad idea, Major.
Thank you.
Mrs. Prudhomme?
Look, I told you people
I don't know where he is, okay?
Mrs. Prudhomme, I'm an MP.
- He's done with all of that.
- It's for his own protection.
He needs my help.
Yeah, well,
he needs all the help he can get,
that's for damn sure.
Does he have any friends?
Places?
Places he hangs out.
Any place there's dope is where.
You have a photo?
Yeah.
You can burn it for all I care.
Good evening.
You followed me in here.
That was a mistake.
And you didn't think
we were watching the wife.
That was a mistake.
Maybe.
So how do you want to do this?
How about one at a time?
I get a baseball bat.
Where's Turner?
Really?
If you were gonna kill me,
you would have done it by now.
Oh, we're not gonna kill you.
Not until you beg for it.
And you're gonna beg.
Left or right?
Turner's gonna call me in two minutes.
If I don't answer, if I don't pick up,
if I sound distressed,
she's in the wind.
You're bluffing.
Go for it.
And now you're wondering
how you're gonna make me talk
without tipping her off.
You can't torture me.
You can't kill me.
And you're definitely
gonna have to kill me.
Give me the phone.
Wait.
Toss it over.
Fellas?
I told you people,
I don't like being followed.
You're good, Jack!
Killing you
isn't gonna be enough, though.
So I'm gonna take back
my promise about
not hurting the little girl.
It's never gonna happen.
Sure it is. One day,
she'll be walking home from school
or she'll be out on a date
or hanging out with her friends.
And you won't be there to protect her.
Okay, so let's try it again.
This time I want you to take the gun
and hold it lower on your chest, okay?
You're holding it a bit too high.
- Okay.
- So grab it.
Yeah, bring it low. That's right.
Now step out and rotate.
- Nice. Good.
- Yeah?
Hi, Reacher. Check this out.
- Ready?
- Yep.
Grab.
- Good. Mmm-hmm.
- Yeah?
What do you think?
Well, trust me,
if all you have left is that move,
just assume you're dead already.
That was good.
Let's try again. We're gonna add
a kick to the balls into it, okay?
Welcome to New Orleans, Captain.
I'm Lieutenant Decoudreau.
We're here to help any way we can.
What do you have for me?
Guys on the plane were ex-military.
Beat up pretty bad.
Do we know who they're working for?
Claim to be unemployed.
Yeah, right.
I want their bank records,
service records, foreign travel,
gun registration, car registration,
how they like their eggs,
their favorite flavor of ice cream.
And I want it yesterday.
Sir, yes, sir.
Is she asleep?
I spoke to Prudhomme's wife.
Turns out he's a junkie.
She didn't know where he was.
But she gave me a photo.
Are you more upset that
I treated you like a woman
or that I treated you like a man?
I'm upset that I didn't deck you.
I should have been the one
to go talk to her.
I can handle myself.
I would've done better.
Maybe.
Appreciate the apology.
Is it really so important that
you make every decision?
Oh, God, you're such a dick.
You know...
Okay, I...
I'm used to working alone.
I'm used to being alone.
Obviously.
I'm trying to apologize.
Go on.
What do you think we should do?
- Don't patronize me, okay?
- I'm asking your opinion.
Well, we could go to the V.A.
Which is the first place
Parasource will look.
How about the local MPs then?
Who'll arrest us in a heartbeat.
Okay, what is your plan then, Reacher?
See, you don't know what to do.
You're like something feral.
You've got their scent in your nose
and all you want is blood.
You still don't get it, do you?
They killed my men,
took away my job, my life!
I don't want them as bad as you,
I want them more.
Could you go see if she's up?
We should get some breakfast,
figure out our next move.
- What do we do with the kid?
- The kid has a name.
I know that.
Why are you so tough on her?
It's a hard world.
The sooner she knows it, the better.
You don't think she knows that already?
Reacher, what if she is yours?
Then I should have been there
15 years ago.
Sam?
Nah, she's not here.
- I'll go get dressed.
- And go where?
Did she say anything to you?
She said she should leave.
What's up?
- Where were you?
- Out.
Are you crazy?
- I was trying to help.
- How were you gonna help, huh?
You guys said Prudhomme's a junkie.
- We never told you...
- I heard you guys talking.
Some dude on the street
said there's a place
in the Ninth Ward
where homeless vets hang out.
Some old warehouse.
People talk to me. It's a thing.
Do you have any idea
how dangerous that was?
I told you I can take care of myself.
Fifteen years old, people are
looking for you, okay.
When things get hairy,
I just pick out the alpha guy.
And what, he's supposed to protect you?
No, I give him shit.
Strong guys don't hurt you.
The weak guys do that.
Strong guys always have little sisters.
Or they want one.
I don't know why, that's just how it is.
I'm really tired.
I can't do this.
That was really stupid.
I know.
Please don't ever do that again.
You're welcome.
Hey.
Let's go find Prudhomme.
Excuse me, sir.
Can you look at this picture, please?
Well, folks call it the
ninth circle of hell.
If he's a vet, that's where he's gonna be.
Thank you.
I have money
for Daniel Prudhomme!
How much?
More than he needs.
Well, how much?
You know Prudhomme?
It depends.
It's a simple question.
What do you want with him?
I told you.
I want to give him money.
You are
Daniel Prudhomme, right?
Specialist Daniel Prudhomme.
Yes, ma'am.
You worked for Parasource.
Now, you spoke to two MPs.
Sergeants Mirkovich and Cibelli.
They interviewed you in Bagram.
No. No, I never heard of them.
Sergeants Mirkovich and Cibelli.
Mirkovich had a six-year-old daughter.
Cibelli's wife is pregnant
with their first.
Now, you're gonna tell me
what happened!
They'll kill me.
She'll kill you.
Now, we'll protect you.
But you have to tell us all of it.
Parasource was running
truck convoys out of Bagram.
We just ran security for the base.
All I had to do was just lie and say
all the weapons were all accounted for.
They gave me a shitload of money
to keep my mouth shut.
We're leavi ng enough shit
over there now
to start another war.
Parasource was selling off the weapons
instead of bringing them
back to the States.
What went wrong?
Warlords want to renegotiate.
Parasource says no.
Next day, we're driving
through those poppy fields.
The whole convoy just gets lit up.
I was scared shitless.
Army had to send in
a Search and Rescue.
Three Search and Rescue dudes
get wasted on the way.
Two of the dudes I knew, man.
What happened
after you gave your statement?
Nothing. I told them everything.
There was this guy.
He worked for Parasource.
He told me not to worry,
that he'd take care of everything.
Next thing I know,
I hear they've been killed.
I went AWOL.
I h itched a ride back to the States.
I was a dead man if I stayed.
I, uh...
I started shooting up over there.
I figured if I'd just
get myself home, you know, I...
I'd get myself right.
But you didn't.
No.
More shit on the streets of New Orleans
than they're making in Afghanistan.
Something's wrong.
- The numbers don't add up.
- What do you mean?
Why put huge government
contracts at risk
while selling U.S. Army weapons
on the black market?
Parasource is smarter than that.
Yeah, they're smart all right.
What about on our end?
Didn't anybody check to see
the crates were empty?
Probably some dumb guy like me.
We need to get inside
one of those transports.
Um...
Plane leaves Bagram
every Friday at 0600 hours.
Six hours to Frankfurt.
Rest, refuel, eleven more to get home.
Jesus, that's 10:00 tonight.
And that was without the hot sauce.
Now, you gotta tell me
that was worth it, sir.
Hey, hey, where you at, chief?
- Ooh, you know, you one fine muffaletta!
- No, no, no.
- No, thank you, ma'am. I'm good.
- Wait a minute.
Now, don't go depriving
a poor girl a taste now.
I have no money.
I don't need your services.
- Not today, darling.
- Okay.
- Well, it's his loss now.
- Go on now.
All right.
- Do I have my wallet?
- Yeah, I think you're good.
All right, I got my wallet.
- You do it?
- Just like we negotiated.
- Well?
- It's done.
Make the call.
Is that you?
No, sir, it's not me.
Who is this?
I have a witness who can exonerate me.
But he has to live first.
Why don't you, uh...
Why don't you come in?
We'll talk about it.
Will you guarantee his safety?
You're not in charge anymore, Major.
Neither are you, apparently.
Operatives have been
ahead of you this whole time.
Who were those guys
on the plane, hmm?
Who tried to kill me in my cell?
Here's a name for you. Parasource.
Here's a couple more names
to think about...
Baghdad. Basra.
It's not our first rodeo, is it, Captain?
You think I want to be
in this position, ma'am?
I have a job to do, and I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna take a leap of faith
that you don't have
anything to do with this.
Look on the back of the phone.
Come alone
and make sure you're not tailed.
Decoudreau to Espin.
This is Espin. Go.
We ID'ed those boys on the plane.
Paid by a shell company
out of the Cayman Islands.
We traced the bank accounts back to
a big military contractor, name of...
Parasource.
Yeah. How'd you know that?
Never mind. Uh...
Give me everything
you can on Parasource,
and I mean everything.
Look, I'm en route to pick up a witness.
We'll send backup.
No, stand ready two minutes out.
Wait for my signal.
That's not procedure, sir.
No, that's called an order.
Reacher knows the game.
If he smells heat, he'll bolt.
All right, we'll stay two minutes out.
What's the address?
Nicholls Street Wharf. Espin out.
Nicholls Street Wharf.
No witnesses.
Freeze!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot, man!
Don't kill me. Don't kill me.
I'm here to help.
- You're the witness?
- Yeah. Yes, yeah, I'm the witness.
Where the hell are you?
- You got what you need?
- Not good enough.
I suggest you listen
to what he has to say.
- I can help.
- Okay. Let's go.
I like stories. Tell me a story.
Now we return to
our Halloween marathon.
Is your costume ready
for tonight's parade?
- I'm gonna call this in.
- I'll cover.
Officer down, Nicholls Wharf.
I'm out.
You're still wanted for murder.
That's right.
I'm a stone killer.
That's why I saved you.
Did Prudhomme give you his statement?
Most of it.
Cibelli and Mirkovich were your friends.
That's right.
Parasource ordered their murders.
They also just tried to kill you.
They've been providing
insurgents with weapons.
You're gonna need more proof
than the word of a dead junkie.
And you're gonna help us get it.
Here. Put the cuffs on,
take us into custody.
Just get us on the tarmac
of Parasource in one hour.
I need you to jump to
a conclusion here, soldier.
Yeah. Thanks.
Okay, here's what we got.
Six months ago, Parasource
loses government contracts
worth over a billion dollars.
They're bleeding cash
and the banks want blood.
But now, all of a sudden,
they start paying back their creditors.
How much money
can they be really making
selling weapons on the black market?
An M4 is, what, five grand?
A rocket launcher's half that.
That's nothing compared to
government contracts.
So where are they
getting the money?
Guest Services.
How may I help you?
Hi, do you have room service?
I'm sorry, I see you paid
cash for your room.
I'm afraid we can't provide incidentals
without a credit card.
U h, yeah, just hold on a second.
You do understand
that the parade is coming
and it may take a while.
That's fine. I'm so starving.
Uh... Is Visa okay?
Sir?
We got a hit on one of the stolen cards.
Hotel Dauphin. 1018 Royal Street.
It's the girl.
I warned him.
IDs?
Captain Anthony Espin,
110th Military Police.
I'm gonna have to call this in.
They're unloading the crates.
We got to get in there.
What's the drill, Major?
Drill is we enforce the law.
Seatbelts, please.
- Turner?
- Major.
Stand down!
I will lay you down, soldier boy!
- Get on the ground!
- Don't move!
- Weapons down!
- Put it down!
Put 'em down, boys, put 'em down.
Take 'em down.
Jeez.
Back off, son.
What is going on here?
You in charge of this operation?
I'm General James Harkness.
I run this company.
We have probable cause
to believe a crime has been committed.
And you are?
Major Susan Turner.
110th Military Police.
The Major Turner who's wanted
by the MPs for espionage?
You mean these MPs?
These crates
are supposed to contain weapons
belonging to the United States Army.
In fact, you sold them to insurgents.
And these are now empty.
Do you know who I am, Major?
Yes, General. I do.
You're the man responsible
for the deaths of two of my men.
Now, open up those crates
before I grab you by your hair plugs
and bitch slap that smug look
off of your face.
What does the manifest say is in there?
AT4 rocket launchers, sir.
Open it.
Open that one.
I said open up that crate!
Open it.
Lieutenant, do your goddamn job
and place this goddamn woman
under arrest.
Sorry, Major, you're gonna
need to come with me.
You're right.
The numbers don't add up.
Sir. Sir.
Stop that man.
- Reacher!
- Stop that man!
Stop him!
Take him down, now!
Deep breath, son.
Pure opium.
Now the numbers add up.
Get him out of here.
Hello.
Good evening. I'm looking for a man,
a woman and a little blonde teenager.
I'm so sorry.
I don't think I can help you
with that type of information.
I'm looking for two adults
and a little blonde girl.
Go find their key.
We have a 4-star
general in custody.
And it's at least 500 kilos.
Sam.
Reacher, it's him. He's here.
- What?
- At the hotel. Hurry.
Sam, listen to me.
Sam? Sam?
Wait, excuse me!
Hey! What are you doing?
Where are you going? Come back here!
She's not answering.
Try again.
Car, car, car, car!
Sam?
She's not in the hotel.
- She's in the street.
- How do you know?
Because that's what I would do.
I'll go this way.
Did you see anything?
Searched the whole hotel.
We didn't find a trace of her.
She's gotta be hiding somewhere.
Reacher.
Let's finish this. Just you and me.
I'm gonna have some fun
with your pretty little girl.
She's not my little girl.
Is that fear I hear in your voice, Jack?
I'm gonna break your arms,
I'm gonna break your legs.
I'm gonna break your neck.
What you hear is excitement.
Hey, you! Get out of there!
Come on. Right now. Out.
Nice try, Jack.
I've found a way to hurt you
like you've never hurt before.
Samantha!
- Do you have her?
- Chartres Street.
Lafitte Hotel.
Sam, run! Run!
Shoot me and I let go!
Shoot me. Shoot me, Jack.
No? Shoot me!
Parasource is done.
Harkness is in custody.
Congratulations, Jack.
I really... I don't give a shit.
Shut up. Shut up!
I told you this would happen.
You said this was about you and me.
Put the gun down.
Okay! Okay. Just...
Okay.
If I put down the gun, you let her go.
My life for hers.
No!
I like it.
Deal, Jack.
It's okay, Sam. Look at me.
It's okay. It's the only way.
It's okay.
I'm gonna put the gun down now.
You know what this means?
It means we're dead already.
Over here.
Kick it over here.
Come on.
Look at me.
You look at me.
Hey.
- Is he all right?
- Yeah, I think so.
Reacher, look here.
I'm right here.
Can you walk?
Sure.
Get the other side.
Dude,
you jumped off a building!
Yeah, I know.
- Did it hurt?
- Yes.
Did you see how high that was?
Can we possibly have this
conversation some other time?
Thank you.
You know, it's funny.
You came here looking for one girl
and you ended up with another.
Let me know how that goes.
I've still got your number.
Bye, Reacher.
Major.
Good to see you back, Major.
Thank you, Captain.
Sorry. Bus got stuck in traffic.
New T-shirt.
Shut up.
Thanks for coming.
So, Reacher,
are you my father or not?
I guess we'll see
when your mother gets here.
Sure you'd recognize her?
I tend to remember
the women I sleep with.
But who says she'll remember you?
Thanks a lot.
You're not my father.
Why do you say that?
See that woman over there?
The waitress who's refilled
your coffee three times?
That's her.
Neither of you had any idea
who the other was.
- I knew it all along.
- No, you didn't.
I'm sure you're relieved.
Not really.
You're just gonna go?
That's right.
Don't you ever get lonely?
Sometimes.
You can call me when you do.
So...
Shouldn't you be...
I'd better go.
Got class.
Drawing.
Yeah, well, you keep that up,
because you're really good at it.
You're really good.
You're gonna be okay, kid.
Well...
See you around, Reacher.